The Shaq is back! Oh, my what a dunk by O'Neal!
He does it all. He is the complete package.
So many moves, so much power.
And it's like a man against boys here tonight.
He will punish you, he's the most dominate player in the game.
Hello everybody. Shaquille O'Neal.
Shaquille O'Neal captured the imagination of the basketball world with overwhelming power and unique athleticism for a man of his stature. Becoming a two time consensus first team All American at Louisiana State University.
Every year at Galaxy, he got better.
Oh, what a pass! Oh!
He didn't want to be good, he wanted to great.
But as impressive as he was in college, when O'Neal hit the NBA in the fall of 1992, we would embark on a mission to become one of the most dominate forces ever to play the game.
When Shaq came into the league, he had such a great passion and enthusiasm for the game. With his size and strength and mobility, it was something that we really hadn't seen.
O'Neal runs the floor. Takes it all the way.
He was huge, he was menacing. He really just attacks the rim.
That's a man's jam buddy.
Shaquille with a grab for that one. Oh, what a dunk!
After collecting the rookie of the year award in 1993, Shaq would win the first of two scoring titles two years later while carrying the Orlando Magic to the NBA Finals. And establishing himself as one of the most engaging personalities the league has ever seen.
He really just took the league by storm, but he did it in Shaquille O'Neal style. He was just as big off the court as he was on the court and when he went from Orlando to the Lakers, L.A. just loved him.
The more bigger I get, I get strong. And the more strong I get, nobody can stop me.
He's this funny, jovial guy, but in between those lines, I mean he's not playing around.
Shaquille, fade away.
He played with such a viciousness. I've watched him put centers to shame.
Shaq brought a whole different element to basketball. He was gonna be the dominate initial force that we had. He took on the mantle of we have to win, now is the time to win.
Kobe on the move, [crosstalk 00:02:44], to the dunk!
The 15 time All Star would be named the league's most valuable player in 2000, the same year he won the first of three straight championships and three NBA Finals MVP awards.
A three-peat for the world champion Los Angeles Lakers!
He put L.A. back on the map. He brought that belief back to Los Angeles that we're playing for titles and nothing else.
Shag the man. The most dominate player in the world.
Shaquille is one of the great Lakers of all time. Over a ten year period, he was the best center in the league. That is absolutely a mark of greatness.
Upon moving on to Miami, the seventh leading scorer in league history added to his resume with a fourth NBA title in 2006.
In the history of big win, he's right in that handful of greatest centers ever.
To win the championships that he's won, the long career, the impact that he has had on the game.
Most defensively dominate player ever to play in this game.
There will never be anybody like Shaquille O'Neal, ever. It won't even be close.